Martynas Gintalas

Data Engineer

Vilnius, Lithuania | Personal website | martynas.gintal@gmail.com

Summary

Data Engineer with expertise in Python, SQL, and cloud solutions. Committed to delivering accurate, efficient data pipelines and continually enhancing data infrastructure.

Skills

Programming Languages: Python, SQL, Shell

Tools & Technologies: Microsoft Fabric, Azure, Git, dbt, Tableau Cloud Platforms: Azure (Azure Storage, Azure DevOps)

Data Engineering: Data pipelines, ETL, CI/CD, Data Migration, Data Modeling

Experience

FL Technics - Data Engineer

Oct 2024 - Present

- Established CI/CD pipelines using Az Devops, ensuring efficient deployment for bronze, silver, and gold environments.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to design scalable data infrastructure.

Danske Bank -

Data Engineer Dec 2023 - Oct 2024
BI Analyst, Senior Apr 2023 - Dec 2023
BI Analyst Nov 2020 - Apr 2023

- Designed and maintained databases, ETL/ELT solutions for operational data, ensuring optimal data delivery.
- Automated ETL processes with SSIS.
- Utilized SQL, Tableau, Python, SSIS, Git, VS Code for ETL processes and dashboard development.
- Collaborated with business users, and internal teams for BI solution alignment and efficient project execution.

KPMG - Audit Associate

Feb 2017 - Apr 2018

- Performed in-depth financial statements' analysis using MS Excel and Access.
- Did financial auditing on mutual fund, banking and manufacturing companies.

Western Union - AML Associate

May 2016 - Jan 2017

- Utilized Excel and Tableau for data processing and presentation.
- Conducted administration and maintenance of customer information, ensuring compliance with AML policies.

Education

Vilnius University - MSc, Finance and Banking / 2020 - 2022

LCC International University - BBA, International Business / 2012 - 2016

Certifications

AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals

CS50: Introduction to programming with Python

Tableau Desktop Specialist